hi welcome back to our alarm room
meditations
uh for our class called
love in the time of the virus and we've
been going through
the 10th chapter the dedication chapter
of master shantidema's guide to the
bodhisattvas way of life
and actually today we're in the final
week of this course
and and we've reached uh
the final part of that chapter uh it's
actually
verses 53 to 58 so it's the very end of
the chapter the whole chapter is
is 58 verses and we're covering the last
five verses now five or six verses
and there are some main ideas here
we are still doing an act of truth so
remember that
uh we are thinking
about some amazing good karma we've done
in the last month or two
in the last few months and we are
grabbing on to that good seed and then
we are kind of using it as a bullet
uh to to shoot the virus you know we are
using
doing an act of truth we're saying it is
true
that during these difficult times and
especially the early times
we were all nervous we were all afraid
we didn't know what was going to happen
and if it's true that during those
difficult times in this country we were
all out of toilet paper
i remember tim gave me them i bowed to
you
and yeah if during those
very difficult times uh you share what
you have
or you're kind to someone else okay
then you have some material you have a
bullet that you can use for your act of
truth okay so
uh during this meditation the first part
we're going to think about some
something nice we did for somebody else
during the virus during the difficult
days especially
and then we're going to take that good
karma like shanti deva did
his good karma was writing the book by
the way the first nine chapters
and and then we're going to dedicate it
that something amazing should happen
and then we'll have a list of amazing
things now the amazing things
are centered around uh this
a special kind of bodhisattva intention
and that's called it's a strange
prayer you know you like i don't know
let's say you're working
i i used to work in a company in new
york and we had a big company
we had about 800 people in the building
and let's say i want to do a real body
stop
a thing and by the way i used to do this
kind of thing i would go to the
bathroom and just sit on top of the
toilet
and uh and do like a five minute
meditation and
so i i i would go into the
bathroom close the door
sit on top of the seat on top of the
cover
and then i would do this five-minute
meditation
and this is a hard one this is a strange
one
and i would think about this company
this busy busy diamond company
hundreds and hundreds of people in the
building right now
working hard we used to work really hard
and of course there's many problems
going on one lady's got cancer
you know the other lady just had lost a
baby
this guy's worried about losing his job
this person just had a divorce all these
kind of things
in this building and we all had stress
and in this building 800 people
everyone's having some kind of thing
going on some kind of problem going on
and sitting here in the toilet stall
i will suck in like a sponge
i will suck in all of their problems for
five minutes
just five minutes okay so this is like a
dharma break you can do
and i like to say that no one ever told
me not to go to the toilet even during
these intense
board meetings uh with the owners and
the investors
it was okay to stand up and leave if
you're gonna go to the toilet
and no one would stop you and and so i
would i would use that as an excuse to
do like
five minute meditation
you know let all the trouble in this
building let all the trouble of 800
people
come into my heart right now okay she's
all coming to me
i will eat all the little and big
problems of the people that i work with
just do it for five minutes you know by
the way don't freak out it's like a
tongue land
of course you should destroy it
with a bright light at the lotus of your
heart you know don't sit there with
800 people's problems inside of you
you're going to get sick or something
okay so
obviously you're supposed to destroy
these problems
but you're supposed to be willing to
take them
which is difficult okay tonight is with
one person
we're talking hundreds of people or
maybe
thousands of people okay so in this last
meditation
we're going to be doing that kind of
that kind of act of truth if it's true
that during the virus i helped someone
then right now may all the problems
of all the people in the whole universe
okay not just the covid people
uh there are billions and billions of
planets like this all of them
i will take all of their trouble
billions and billions of planets worth
of beings
and not just people all the animals
birds
insects bacteria i would take all of
them probably the cobians running around
wishing he could live also right
so i i would take all of the i'll take
the covid
viruses personal problems
i will take them on myself and uh
happily i will take them on myself
and this is this is an act of this is an
act of truth
if it's true that i did something nice
during the virus then
by that power should i have the power
should i have the strength
to take on all the problems of billions
of planets worth of people
and if you want an image for it we can
take it from seiji's
book which is called the crown of knives
and in fact it was an instruction
granted to lord artesha by his teacher
who is
dharma and uh so
you know we've been talking about lord
aftershow a lot and
so he he got a poem from his own teacher
just before he went to this crazy
country called
tibet and to take care of the people
there
and this teacher said you're going to
need this poem you know here's a poem
to make you feel better when you go to
all this wild tibetans and
so uh in that
text uh they referred to a thing called
the
uh the crown of knives crown of knives
sometimes they call real or sharp
weapons i i i like crowning knives
better
because of an ancient story which we
translated
and by the way that book is coming out
soon i think
the translation was finished yesterday
the final editing and final editing has
to be done but there's a story
in an ancient sutra called all the kinds
of karma karma b banga
which talks about all the correlations
there are there's a story in there
of a young man who decided to take on
the pain
of the world you know he was about to be
murdered by a special
like ninja star wheel big one
that was about to chop into his head
like a crown of knives
and just before the crown of knives came
to his head he
he made a prayer may i take all the pain
of of all the
of all the people especially my mother
and my father
and here you see the wheel and we're
using this wheel picture here
so let's go let's start just remember
the general strategy
we're going to think of a good thing we
did
during the virus then we're going to do
an act of truth if it's true
that i helped people during the virus
that i was unselfish during the virus
then may my dreams come true what are
your dreams
my dream is that i can take all the pain
of the whole universe on me
okay okay that's kind of a strange dream
but
okay i hope i hope it works okay all
right
so here we go all right so get ready
for meditation sit up straight
i like a small smile on my face
and the forehead is relaxed
just be here don't think about all the
stuff you have to do
we all have stuff to do and we all die
in the middle of it so don't get too
attached to it
pulling your tummy
shoulders back hands back on the thighs
and we'll do 10 long exhales to get into
the meditation
so please remember some kindness
you did for somebody else during the
time of the virus
now we're going to do an act of truth if
it's true
that i paid this kindness
to people during the virus
then first of all may i meet manjushri
may i meet that
exquisite angel a
beautiful beautiful angel
who is made of all the wisdom
of the buddhas all the the wisdom of all
the buddhas
okay may i meet manjushri if it's true
that i was kind during the virus then
may i personally meet manjushri
face to face
and may i be like him may i have this
bodhisattva intention
may i have this experience of meeting
all beings and
[Music]
assuring them that i will take care of
them
here comes the big part of this
meditation
if it's true i did do some small
kindness
during the virus then may
all the problems of all beings
ripen on me may i take all their bad
seeds
into me and it feels very good okay it
sounds
frightening it sounds like it would be a
lot of trouble and
normally we are trying to escape trouble
but there's a certain beauty extreme
beauty
to purposely and anonymously
taking other people's problems away from
them and taking them on ourselves
it's a little difficult to start
but once you do it it feels so right
that it becomes easy and it becomes
extremely satisfying
if it's true i did a little thing
during the virus times for somebody else
then may i have the blessing of the
ability
to take on other people's troubles
this is a big universe this plan is not
the only place there is
there are countless other bodhisattvas
in the universe there are many many
countless cannot count them
amazing wonderful people on many many
different planets
so let's do an act of truth for them
which is what
master shantideva does here
if it's true that i did a small good
thing
during the days of the virus if i had
love
during the time of the virus then
may all the dreams and all the plans
of all those bodhisattvas to help the
people on their own planets
come true made their dreams made their
plans
come true
by the power of my good deed
these ideas are extremely unusual
you know for someone for all of us
to sit here and pray
that people's troubles should come to us
it's a very very unusual
philosophy unusual way of life
but if it became more
widespread
in this world then the whole world would
be much happier
it's much more it makes you much happier
to serve other people than to take
things from other people
it's it makes your whole life sweet
and and fulfill
[Music]
and if only this kind of thinking
strange
beautiful thinking could spread in this
world
you know i i will do an act of truth if
i was nice to someone
during the days of the virus then this
strange beautiful idea
that i should take the troubles of other
people should spread
in this world and make this world a
happy world
in the final verse of the guide to the
bodhisattva's way of life
master shantideva bows down to his own
teacher
who is manjushri really
so we can do that together let's bow
down
to this divine being who is made of
love bodhichitta
and an understanding of seeds and
emptiness
okay and slowly open your eyes
take a good stretch okay we'll do this
meditation
for the whole last week try to do it
twice a day
okay and you'll be very happy
and try to read that chapter or
if if you want to you can listen to the
recording
and try to listen to that once or twice
a day okay
see you then